hi I'm ed burns in this session I'm
嗨，我在本次会议上被烫伤，
going to talk to you about building a
打算和您谈谈建立一个
service state service for the cloud a
云服务状态服务
little bit about me I've been doing
我一直在做的关于我的事
software development for over 25 years
软件开发超过25年
you may know me from the Java EE realm
您可能从Java EE领域了解我
I was the spec lead for JavaServer faces
我是JavaServer Faces的规范负责人
and servlet for many years and I'm very
和servlet很多年了，我非常
happy to be helping to hand off those
很高兴能帮助交出那些
items to the Eclipse project for EE for
Eclipse项目的EE项目
Jay I'm really excited that the
周杰伦，我真的很兴奋
community is going to be carrying these
社区将承担这些
things forward we've got some exciting
前进的事情，我们有些激动
things planned I've been a frequent
我经常去计划的事情
speaker at conferences and I often like
在会议上做演讲者，我经常喜欢
to teach a workshop whenever I go to
每当我去时都会教一个工作坊
conferences as well and I right now I'm
会议以及我现在
happy to be working on this state
很高兴在这种状态下工作
service that I'm talking to you about
我正在与您谈论的服务
today we have a great team staffed with
今天我们有一支很棒的团队
people that are behind oracle coherence
甲骨文一致性背后的人
this was a product that oracle has long
这是甲骨文长期以来的产品
had great success with with our
与我们取得了巨大的成功
customers and and running it ourselves
客户并自己运行
for various business purposes that we
为了各种商业目的，我们
run on and when we talking a lot more
继续，当我们谈论更多
about that in the session I've written a
关于这一点，我写了一个
few books from mcgraw-hill and so let's
麦格劳-希尔的几本书，所以让我们
get on to the next slide this is our
转到下一张幻灯片，这是我们的
boring safe harbor statement but very
无聊的安全港声明，但非常
important in this session because I'm
在这次会议上很重要，因为我
going to be showing you code and api's
将向您显示代码和api
but this is still in development so we
但这仍在发展中，因此我们
don't have our final form for this yet
还没有我们的最终表格
so expect it to change these are some
所以期望它能改变这些
pictures of things that are useless
没用的东西的图片
coffee pot made of chocolate that would
用巧克力做的咖啡壶
obviously melt and a spoon that you
显然融化，汤匙，你
can't I'm sorry a fork that you can't
抱歉，你不能
pick up and
拿起
watering jug that you really can't force
你真的不能强迫的水壶
stuff out of a square wheel the
东西从方轮
archetypal example of something that's
某些东西的原型例子
useless in software there is a lot of
在软件中没有用，有很多
buzz and and justified buzz about doing
关于这样做的嗡嗡声和合理的嗡嗡声
stateless services because let's face it
无状态服务，因为我们面对现实
state does bring with it a lot of
国家确实带来了很多
problems you have to deal with
您必须处理的问题
concurrency issues you have to deal with
您必须处理的并发问题
mutability you have to deal with
您必须应对的可变性
scalability problems that all really
真正的可扩展性问题
stems from having to deal with state so
源于必须与国家打交道
there's a lot to be said about stateless
关于无状态，有很多话要说
applications oh let's not cry like a
哦，别哭了
baby here what can you do without state
宝贝在这里，你可以没有状态怎么办
all right people are clearly making
好人都清楚
great progress in stateless systems you
无状态系统的巨大进步
can basically convert input to output
基本上可以将输入转换为输出
that's what a pure function does right
这就是纯函数所做的正确的事情
in the mathematical sense when it comes
从数学意义上讲
to building software applications to
建立软件应用程序以
deal with state you can make that the
处理状态，您可以使
caller's problem since what we call the
呼叫者的问题，因为我们称之为
hot potato problem you just pass the
你刚刚通过的热土豆问题
state on as you do something with it or
在您做某事时声明或
you can externalize the state this is
您可以将状态外部化
the approach that most people use in
大多数人使用的方法
production and this is indeed the
生产，这确实是
approach that we have advocating here
我们在这里提倡的方法
with the state service
与国家服务
it is externalize the problem when you
当您将问题外部化时
do that is you have to really have a
这样做是因为您必须真正拥有
system that is utterly consistent and is
完全一致的系统
also very high-performing and I believe
表现也非常好，我相信
this state service I'm talking about to
我正在谈论的这个国家服务
you is both of these things before we
在我们之前，你就是这两个东西
get to state let's talk about state and
进入状态，让我们谈谈状态和
serverless serverless itself is a bit of
无服务器无服务器本身有点
a marketing term really it just means
一个营销术语，实际上意味着
there are servers still but the servers
仍然有服务器，但是服务器
are somebody else's problem I'm very
是别人的问题，我非常
fond of referencing the somebody else's
喜欢提及别人的
problem field from the Hitchhiker's
旅行者的问题领域
Guide to the galaxy here somebody else's
银河指南在这里别人的
problem field is much simpler and more
问题领域更简单，更多
effective and what's more it can be run
有效，而且可以运行
for over 100 years in a single charge
一次充电超过100年
battery so this is from Hitchhiker's
电池，这是来自旅行者的
Guide to the galaxy and you erect to
星系指南，你直立到
somebody else's problem
别人的问题
around something you don't want anyone
周围的东西你不想要任何人
to see because when they see it they
看到，因为当他们看到它时
really will be like I don't want to mess
真的就像我不想弄乱
with that it's somebody else's problem
这是别人的问题
it comes back to what we've been doing
回到我们一直在做的事情
in software and business software for
在软件和商业软件中
forever which is the relentless drive to
永远是不懈的追求
allow developers to focus on business
允许开发人员专注于业务
logic we've been trying to reduce
我们一直试图减少的逻辑
boilerplate pretty much since we
因为我们
invented boilers this idea is separating
发明这种想法的锅炉是分开的
the stuff you need to get to the point
你需要的东西要点
where your business logic runs from the
您的业​​务逻辑从
actual business logic you allows you to
您允许您使用的实际业务逻辑
focus on the core business logic and
专注于核心业务逻辑和
this goes back to the beginning of
这可以追溯到
programming languages the very idea of
编程语言的想法
separating the core language from the
将核心语言与
runtime libraries you know it started
您知道它开始的运行时库
probably before C but C is a really good
可能在C之前，但是C真的很好
example C is so close to a seminal
例子C如此接近开创性
language I had a CS professor in college
我在大学有CS教授的语言
and would you say C is assembly language
你会说C是汇编语言
and that's a NASA portable statement
那是NASA的可移植声明
it's an accurate statement and it has it
这是一个准确的陈述
set the separation of the core language
设置核心语言的分离
to the runtime libraries in the
到
enterprise software world and
企业软件世界和
particularly in Java but not just Java
特别是在Java中，而不仅仅是Java
we could say the serverless
我们可以说无服务器
is the logical extension of dependency
是依赖关系的逻辑扩展
injection so dependency injection is
注入，所以依赖注入是
where it sits you know was the
它坐在那里你知道
state-of-the-art for allowing you to
最先进的技术让您
separate business logic from everything
将业务逻辑与一切分离
else in 2002 came into the fore in the
否则在2002年脱颖而出
Java world with spring JSF had it around
春季JSF的Java世界
the same time 2004 and the idea with
与2004年同一时间和
dependency injection is you have your
依赖注入是你有你的
core code and you just say you know
核心代码，您只是说您知道
inject the business logic and you have
注入业务逻辑，您就可以
the business logic and inject
业务逻辑和注入
dependencies that it needs into it
它需要的依赖
this has manifest benefits testing
这有明显的好处测试
testability is one of them because you
可测试性就是其中之一，因为您
your core code can be run in different
您的核心代码可以在不同的位置运行
contexts in a test context
测试上下文中的上下文
runtime context and in each case you
运行时上下文，在每种情况下，您
have different dependencies you for
有不同的依赖关系
example mock objects this was further
示例对象，这是进一步
standardized in the Java world in 2009
2009年在Java世界中标准化
when we had containerization I'm sorry
当我们进行集装箱运输时，我很抱歉
when we had the ad inject jsr 3:30 this
当我们有广告注入jsr 3:30这
standardized the notion of dependency
标准化依赖概念
injection moving further along in time
注射随着时间的推移进一步发展
to Tanner is a ssin started to become
对坦纳来说，是一个罪恶开始
popular around 2014 or so and this was
在2014年左右流行，这是
yet another example of the kind of right
权利的另一个例子
place at the right time effect the cloud
在正确的时间放置影响云
platforms were maturing and
平台日趋成熟，
containerization was kind of a perfect
集装箱化是一个完美的选择
idea for packaging applications in the
包装应用中的想法
cloud so it's another way to sort of
云，这是另一种方式
have dependency injection you have your
有依赖注入，你有
core code and all the stuff around it
核心代码及其周围的所有内容
isn't really much concern because you're
并不是很在乎，因为你是
running inside a container which itself
在本身本身的容器内运行
is running in the cloud at this point
此时正在云中运行
though I think I've convinced you that
虽然我认为我已经说服了你
you do need some state so now where does
您确实需要一些状态，所以现在在哪里
it go let's look at the history of these
让我们来看看这些的历史
things just like we have had a
就像我们曾经经历过的
separation between core language and
核心语言与
runtime libraries state has always been
运行时库状态始终为
somewhat divorced from the core
有点脱离核心
programming language code was always you
编程语言代码一直都是你
know the grunt the behavior was the code
知道行为是代码
and the state was the data it started
状态是它开始的数据
out really with from simple text files
从简单的文本文件中取出
that were read
被阅读
you know from tape drives and got
你从磁带机上知道了
further refined with the introduction of
通过引入进一步完善
structured query language SQL now there
结构化查询语言SQL现在在那里
it was a domain-specific language dealt
这是处理特定领域的语言
with dealing with state and you know if
与国家打交道，你知道
you wanted to deal with it in your
你想在你的身上处理它
programming language code it was you
编程语言代码就是你
know you could do it it was fine you
知道你可以做到，你很好
would have to have either SQL injection
将不得不进行SQL注入
of some kind or
某种或
maybe use an object-relational mapping
可能使用对象关系映射
technology but the point was you're
技术，但关键是你
always creating SQL statements and
总是创建SQL语句和
sending them off to the database which
将它们发送到数据库
is separate from the code right this got
与代码分开是正确的
a little more refined when the so called
当所谓的
no SQL approaches and document style
没有SQL方法和文档样式
databases we have you know up here on
我们在这里知道的数据库
the upper right Oracle cloud database
右上方的Oracle云数据库
MongoDB DynamoDB this kind of seeing as
MongoDB DynamoDB这种看似
a logical progression of things now we
现在事物的逻辑发展
know we need state but what you need
知道我们需要状态但是您需要什么
from a store of state let's talk about a
从州立商店谈起
few operations type things but your
很少有操作会输入内容
operations had on here so you want to
操作已经在这里，所以你想
have durability if you know either your
如果您知道自己的
client disconnects and comes back or
客户端断开连接并回来或
some of the nodes go down in the data
一些节点在数据中下降
cluster you don't lose any data
集群您不会丢失任何数据
everything is perfectly durable of
一切都非常耐用
course you want to have reliability and
当然你要有可靠性和
high availability so when it comes back
高可用性，因此回来时
it's durable but the fact that it comes
它很耐用，但事实是
back at all is reliable the fact that it
完全可以信赖的事实是
fails over without even noticing or a
故障转移甚至没有引起注意或
very minimal degradation in service
服务降级很小
uptime is important scalability number
正常运行时间是重要的可扩展性数字
of the ability to increase the
的能力
processing capability as the load
处理能力作为负载
increases we'll get to more on that when
增加，我们将在以下方面获得更多
we talk about the cloud aspects of it
我们谈论它的云方面
and the throughput of course number of
和课程数量的吞吐量
requests per second for example in place
每秒请求数
processing that is you want to operate
您要操作的处理
on the data where the data is so you
在数据所在的位置上，您
don't want to have to take your compute
不想拿你的电脑
and suck the data in what you really
并以您真正的方式吸取数据
want to do is send your compute to where
想做的就是将您的计算机发送到哪里
the data is do the querying and
数据是查询和
aggregation and manipulation there and
在那里聚集和操纵
send the results back
将结果发回
that's what M plays processing is
这就是M播放的过程
aquarium aggregations this is a
水族馆聚集这是一个
programming level concern where you you
编程级别关注您在哪里
know obviously all of this exists in SQL
知道所有这些显然都存在于SQL中
we would like to have a system that is a
我们希望拥有一个
little closer to the core programming of
更接近于核心编程
gideon's that will have there
基甸的在那里
of that system you would like to be able
您想要的系统
to listen for map events for example and
监听地图事件，例如
make sure that it's done the highly
确保它做的高度
performant way and it needs to be
性能的方式，它需要
accessible with the programming language
可通过编程语言访问
of choice so this is the so-called
选择，所以这就是所谓的
polyglot multi language use case that's
多语言多语言用例
just the core requirements of the state
只是国家的核心要求
service what would you need on top of
服务您还需要什么
that when you take it into the cloud
当您将其带入云端时
well on-demand provisioning and
良好的按需配置和
elasticity you only want to of course
当然只需要弹性
pay for what you use and not what you're
支付您使用的费用，而不是您所用的费用
not using that's the whole rationale of
不使用那是整个理由
the cloud in the first place you want to
首先要云
have a server this operating paradigm
有一个服务器这种操作模式
that is the management is handled by the
那就是管理是由
vendor you don't have to manage it
供应商，您不必管理它
yourself you want to have pay-as-you-go
你自己你想要随付随付
and utility computing pricing and you
和公用事业计算定价，您
want to have a smooth on-ramp you know
想有一个平稳的入口
in the local development case to the
在当地发展的情况下
cloud development case you want to have
您想要的云开发案例
similar abilities for your pipelines
您的管道具有类似的功能
your development pipelines to feed into
您的开发管道可以输入
those things so what's wrong with using
这些东西，所以使用有什么问题
our existing language specific data
我们现有的特定语言数据
structures most importantly map also
结构最重要的是还要映射
known as dictionary hash container
被称为字典哈希容器
associative array every language has
每种语言都有的关联数组
this concept it really has everything
这个概念真的包含了一切
you need it's got rows and columns the
您需要它的行和列
fields that is and its key centric which
领域及其关键中心
means it will be very scalable but the
意味着它将非常可扩展，但是
problem of all of these so far is that
到目前为止，所有这些的问题是
they're stuck on the heap you want to be
它们卡在您想成为的堆上
able to take that concept and expand it
能够接受并扩展这个概念
so that it's not succumbing ok let's
这样就不会屈服了，让我们
drill into why hash maps are great right
深入了解为什么哈希图非常合适
so they've got the the foundation
所以他们有基础
concept in computer science of the hash
哈希计算机科学中的概念
function if you want to take that and
功能，如果你想采取和
make it accessible and usable in a
使它在
multi-threaded environment the simplest
多线程环境最简单
way in Java is just to say collections
Java中的方式只是说集合
that synchronize map of map this keeps
保持地图同步的地图
the hashing semantics and provides the
哈希语义，并提供
thread safe but it's very coarse in
线程安全，但在其中非常粗糙
terms of contention every operation from
每个操作的竞争条件
every client
每个客户
is serialized synchronized and executed
被序列化同步并执行
in serial concurrent hash map is a
在串行并发哈希图中是
little bit better it only locks things
好一点，它只能锁定东西
operation basis so it's in process and
操作基础，因此它正在进行中
it's much more granular in its
它的粒度更细
contention than synchronized map so
争夺比同步地图好
let's introduce cloud map it has the
让我们介绍一下它的云图
same hashing semantics as concurrent app
与并发应用相同的哈希语义
but it's highly distributed multi
但是高度分散
process and multi thread and I'll
进程和多线程，我将
explain how we can do that and that's
解释我们如何做到这一点，那就是
where the magic of coherence comes into
凝聚力的神奇之处
play but the programming experience is
玩，但编程经验是
just a map based API that we plan to
只是我们计划基于地图的API
produce as one of the state service
作为国家服务之一
api's I mean in the local case right so
api的意思是在当地情况下
I've mentioned these before a simple
我已经简单地提到了这些
hash right hash map is you have a table
哈希右哈希图，你有一张桌子吗
where you perform a hash on the key hash
您在密钥哈希上执行哈希的位置
function modulo the length of the table
函数对表的长度取模
and that gives you a new entry and the
这会给您一个新条目，并且
concurrent hash map we lock that
并发哈希图，我们将其锁定
particular bucket that you're dealing
您要处理的特定存储桶
with and then the distributed hash map
然后是分布式哈希图
we have a very nice patented hashing
我们有一个非常好的专利哈希
algorithm that comes inside of coherence
一致性内在的算法
that does the hash which maps to a
进行映射到
partition which is you know also known
你知道的分区也知道
as a bucket or a specific member in a
作为桶或某个特定成员
and that is the data partition where
那是数据分区
your your data lives so in a distributed
您的数据生活在分布式环境中
context you can have multiple nodes many
上下文中您可以有多个节点
nodes coherence run thousands of nodes
节点一致性运行数千个节点
you could have even easily and only the
您甚至可以轻松拥有
node that has the data is the one that
有数据的节点就是那个
has to be locked so you can think of
必须锁定，以便您可以想到
climb app as the distributed map plus
爬升应用程序作为分布式地图，再加上
plus it's the circle of state service
再加上国家服务界
it's running on top of Oracle's
它运行在Oracle的
bare-metal cloud and it is running on
裸金属云，它正在运行
top of oracle coherence
甲骨文的一致性
I mentioned the many years we've
我提到我们已经有很多年了
experienced that we've put inside of
经历过我们投入的
coherence to have site reliability
具有站点可靠性的一致性
engineering inside you can think of it
您可以想到的内部工程
as a Serena box
作为Serena盒子
all right many languages let's take a
好吧，许多语言让我们来
look at a demo here first I want to show
我想先在这里看一个演示
the local development use case let's
本地开发用例，让我们
take a look at the local development
看看当地的发展
story for the state service
国家服务的故事
we followed in the example of the FN
我们以FN为例
project our serverless functions as a
将我们的无服务器功能投影为
service effort and we have a local
服务努力，我们在当地
command line
命令行
ours is called CM which is the name will
我们的名字叫CM，就是这个名字
probably change but it stands for cloud
可能会改变，但代表云
map currently and it has a number of
当前的地图，它具有多个
commands and first we're just going to
命令，首先我们要去
create a local instance see I'm create -
创建本地实例，请参阅我正在创建-
p5 to do this we have a to-do
p5为此，我们有一个要做的事情
application I'll be covering that in
应用程序，我将在
great detail the p5 is a partition
p5是一个分区，非常详细
account which is a reference to the
帐户，它是对
underlying industrial strength coherence
潜在的产业实力一致性
technology that we have behind this
我们背后的技术
thing you can see that when we started
你可以看到，当我们开始
it up we have two different ports
它有两个不同的端口
exposed G RPC and a management port and
公开的G RPC和管理端口，以及
the G RPC is really important because it
G RPC非常重要，因为它
leverages this very popular current
利用了这一非常流行的潮流
technology for doing a remote procedure
远程程序的技术
call this gives us a lot of benefits
称这给我们带来很多好处
which I'll be showing today but one of
我今天要展示的是其中之一
them is multi-language support and
它们是多语言支持，
that's a really important thing as I
这对我来说真的很重要
mentioned earlier the management port we
前面提到的管理端口
interact with that in several different
与其他几种互动
ways
方法
via rest and also via maven so let's
通过休息以及通过Maven，让我们
just take a look at the demo that we
看看我们的演示
have we're going to start it out we have
我们要开始吗
several different language versions of
的几种不同语言版本
it here but there one I'm going to show
它在这里，但我要展示
first is the node based one and p.m.
首先是基于节点的一个和pm
start and this is a simple to do
开始，这很简单
application using react JSON
使用react JSON的应用程序
and node in the middle tier and state
和节点在中间层和状态
service in the back tier for expedience
后台服务，方便快捷
we use facebook login to get us the
我们使用Facebook登录获取我们
username of the current user you can add
您可以添加当前用户的用户名
a few items let's pretend it's a
让我们假装这是一个
shopping list milk cookies and peanut
购物清单牛奶饼干和花生
butter
牛油
we'll cover the UI itself more detail
我们将详细介绍UI本身
later but I want to show here is the
稍后，但我想展示的是
live code deployment feature so if we
实时代码部署功能，如果我们
click on this we expect it to check it
点击这个，我们希望它检查一下
off it's done however we notice that
完成，但是我们注意到
it's not doing anything well that's
它做得不好
because I haven't deployed the portion
因为我还没有部署
of the code that deals with the entry
处理条目的代码
processor that does the check off of the
执行检查的处理器
thing so let's look at what that code
事情，所以让我们看看该代码是什么
looks like I mentioned the middle tiers
看起来像我提到的中间层
written in node and the back end is
写在节点上，后端是
entirely just the state service so the
完全是国家服务，所以
only application code that's on the back
背面只有应用程序代码
end here is this little entry processor
在这里结束的是这个小入口处理器
now the entry processor is a core
现在入口处理器是核心
concept of coherence and also the cloud
连贯性以及云的概念
map and the state service and it gives
地图和国家服务，它给
you the ability to have server-side
您具有服务器端的能力
processing for your data manipulation
处理您的数据操作
code I'll talk about the numerous
代码我将讨论众多
benefits of that elsewhere in the
在其他地方的好处
presentation but for now we can just say
演示文稿，但现在我们只能说
that we are implementing the entry
我们正在实施该条目
processor interface which has one method
具有一种方法的处理器接口
called process and this is handed a map
叫做过程，这是一张地图
entry now at our domain application here
现在进入我们的域名申请表
the data structure is a string mapped to
数据结构是映射到的字符串
a JSON object and the string is a UUID
JSON对象，字符串为UUID
that's created by the client and the
由客户和
JSON object is just a little bit of JSON
JSON对象只是JSON的一小部分
representing that to do in our case it's
代表我们要做的是
super simple it's a boolean for the
超级简单，这是一个布尔值
checkbox the user ID for whom this to do
选中要执行此操作的用户标识
is to be accounted for and the text of
将被考虑和的文本
the to do so we're handed this and all
为此，我们将这一切
we want to do is obtain the value of the
我们要做的就是获取
completed property
完工的财产
- do not get completed because you can
-不要完成，因为可以
see it's a JSON map so we can just
看到它是一个JSON映射，所以我们可以
obtain the completed property there we
在这里获取完成的财产
want to flip it and store it back again
想要翻转并再次存储回去
so it's not been deployed so how do we
所以它还没有被部署
deploy it well it's maven so you can
很好地部署它是行家，因此您可以
just simply do a maven deploy and we
只是简单地进行Maven部署，我们
have I mentioned the management port
我有提到管理端口吗
it's listening about 8080 that is a
它正在听大约8080
maven repository so let's just run maven
Maven存储库，所以让我们运行Maven
deploy maven - yes I have a settings
部署Maven-是的，我有一个设置
file and deploy and you can see it's
文件并部署，您可以看到
going to be super fast okay it's been
很快就会过去的
deployed now this is the two-step
现在部署这是两个步骤
process we have to go back to the CM
过程，我们必须回到CM
command you can see that we had cm
命令，您可以看到我们有厘米
activate so this takes the maven group
激活，因此需要Maven组
ID artifact ID and version and makes it
ID工件的ID和版本，并使其
available for the code to run I have it
可用于运行的代码我有它
in my history here cm activate comm
在我的历史记录中，cm会激活通讯
Oracle cloud applications examples -
Oracle云应用程序示例-
dues as the group ID to do server is the
作为服务器的组ID是应缴费用
artifact ID and 100 is the version to be
工件ID，100是要发布的版本
extra pedantic let's just compare that
让我们来比较一下
with the pom and you can see it's the
与绒球，你可以看到它是
same so we're activating it we got our
同样，所以我们激活它，我们得到了
200 ok
200 OK
and now when we check these things it
现在当我们检查这些东西时
checks off and I didn't have to redeploy
检查一下，我不必重新部署
anything I didn't have to restart
我不需要重启的所有内容
anything I just had to deploy the maven
我只需要部署Maven的任何东西
artifact and activate it now let's say
现在启动它并激活它
we're in a cloud situation of course
我们当然处于云中
this is the cloud map and we deploy
这是云图，我们部署
early - poor often it's a lot of
早期-贫穷常常很多
deployment here in the cloud so we're
部署在云端
going to just make a new version of this
要做一个新的版本
thing and we will you know as sometimes
事情，我们有时会知道
happens introduced a bug so thankfully
碰巧引入了一个错误，所以谢天谢地
in the micro services world there are
在微服务世界中
many techniques such as canary testing
金丝雀测试等许多技术
and Bluegreen deployments and any number
和Bluegreen部署以及任何数量
of other cute names
其他可爱的名字
you mitigate the effects of this but in
您减轻了这种影响，但在
our simple case we're just gonna roll it
我们的简单情况下，我们只是要滚动它
back
背部
so let's deploy it with the bug in place
因此，让我们在存在错误的情况下进行部署
and it should prevent it from running
它应该阻止它运行
again we won't be able to toggle it in
再次，我们将无法切换它
this case oh yes I forgot almost forgot
这种情况哦，是的，我忘了几乎忘了
I have to increment the version number
我必须增加版本号
because this is maven after all and
因为毕竟这是行家
versions are immutable so if I was to
版本是一成不变的，所以如果我要
try to deploy this I would get a 500
尝试部署这个我会得到500
error or something like that
错误或类似的东西
access denied I'm not exactly sure which
访问被拒绝，我不确定
one we've got it set to right now okay
我们已经将其设置为现在
we've deployed that let's inactivate 101
我们已经部署了101
okay we got it 200 okay and let's click
好吧，我们得到200好，让我们单击
this and it doesn't work and we click
这，它不起作用，我们单击
this and that doesn't work either okay
这个，那也不行，好吧
well that's a problem let's roll it back
好吧，这是一个问题，让我们回滚
so we don't have to deploy anything else
所以我们不必部署其他任何东西
we can simply go back to version 100 and
我们可以简单地回到100版本，
click on this and now you can see it
点击这个，现在你可以看到它
works again so it's really important
再次工作，所以真的很重要
that you know you can see that we didn't
你知道你可以看到我们没有
have to restored anything and it's a
必须恢复任何东西，这是一个
very highly dynamic system finally on
高度动态的系统终于在
the last bit I want to mention on the CM
我想在CM上提到的最后一点
local development story right now we're
现在的当地发展故事
not using these things but we will be
不使用这些东西，但我们会
using this for castrator URL to point to
使用此命令将施法者URL指向
the cloud server that might be a load
可能是负载的云服务器
balanced end point for our service and
我们服务的平衡终点
also we'll have a core support for
我们也将对
worker everything we're doing in the
工人我们在做的一切
Oracle developer experience is really
Oracle开发人员经验真的是
trying to leverage a lot of other great
试图利用很多其他伟大的东西
cloud technologies I'll be talking about
我将要讨论的云技术
bare metal cloud but we also are going
裸金属云，但我们也要去
to be leveraging worker which is a
要利用工人
really great pipeline technology that we
我们真正伟大的管道技术
have
有
let's take a look at the multi-language
让我们来看看多国语言
support by looking at the three
通过三个方面的支持
different two new clients that we've
我们有两个不同的新客户
implemented so far we've already seen
到目前为止，我们已经实现了
the JavaScript base one over here up
JavaScript在此之上
here we have a textual one written and
在这里，我们写了一篇文本，
go and down here we have a Java based
上下下来，我们有一个基于Java的
one written in Java FX let's look at the
用Java FX编写的一个让我们看一下
go one first
先去
it's textual so we have a little CLI you
这是文本，所以我们有一个小的CLI
can say list to list your items to get
可以说清单列出您要获得的物品
and you can say add to add a new item so
您可以说添加以添加新项目
let's change let's add grapes and you
让我们改变，让我们添加葡萄，你
can see when I've added it here it shows
可以看到我在这里添加它的时间
up over here in JavaFX and also in the
在JavaFX以及此处
node one this is because we have a
节点一，这是因为我们有一个
full-featured event service in the state
该州功能齐全的事件服务
service but I'll show more in the code
服务，但我将在代码中显示更多
section but it basically uses the
部分，但它基本上使用
capabilities of the language that you're
您所用语言的功能
in and has a reactive based event system
并具有基于反应的事件系统
that allows streaming and filtering and
允许流式传输和过滤，以及
all sorts of great things that you come
各种伟大的事物
to expect when you deal with data
期待何时处理数据
structures and maps in Java and I can't
Java中的结构和地图，我做不到
say enough how we're taking the ease of
说够了，我们如何放松
use of the collections and map API in
使用集合和map API
particular as a guide and adding some
特别作为指导并添加一些
additional features on top of that we
除此之外，我们还有其他功能
want the user experience to be very
希望用户体验非常
seamless and not have to require you to
无缝的，而不必要求您
think of different paradigms to interact
考虑不同的范式进行交互
with State ok I mentioned you can had
好吧，我提到你可以
items you can also edit items so let's
项目，您还可以编辑项目，所以让我们
list will change edit one to chunky
列表会将编辑内容更改为大块
peanut butter and you can see it updated
花生酱，你可以看到它更新了
there you can mark and unmarked them so
在那里您可以标记和未标记它们
let's say we got cookies mark two and
假设我们的Cookie标记为两个，
let's say we also got grapes mark three
假设我们也获得了葡萄标志三
okay so you can remove also from the
好的，所以您也可以从
list so we don't need milk anymore we
列出，所以我们不再需要牛奶了
got a text and someone else bought it in
收到了短信，然后有人买了
the family and the chunky peanut butter
家庭和矮胖的花生酱
we do want that still so we check that
我们仍然想要那个，所以我们检查一下
off and you can also say clear completed
关闭，您也可以说清除完成
now we've got no events so I'll just add
现在我们没有任何活动，所以我只添加
a few more and just show the different
多一些，只是显示不同
filtering we can do so now it's the
过滤，我们现在可以这样做
evening so we're going to be getting
晚上，所以我们要去
some more fun stuff we'll get some beer
一些更有趣的东西，我们会喝啤酒
get some wine cheese and crackers having
吃一些葡萄酒奶酪和饼干
a little tasting party here so we'll
这里有一个小小的品尝会，所以我们会
check off every other one and then say
互相检查一下然后说
hey she'll only the completed ones
嘿，她只会完成的
that's going to show you just the
这将向您展示
checked ones and the active ones are the
选中的和活动的是
unchecked ones ones we still haven't
未选中的那些我们仍然没有
gotten and that's a quick tour of the UI
得到了，这是对UI的快速浏览
let's take a look at the code of the
让我们来看看
three different clients first we'll
首先是三个不同的客户
examine how each of them connects to the
检查他们每个人如何连接到
state service it's very similar in each
状态服务在每个方面都非常相似
case first up here we have the node
案例首先在这里，我们有节点
JavaScript 1 we have a cloud map which
JavaScript 1我们有一张云图
is part of the API that we provide you
是我们为您提供的API的一部分
ask it for a session passing the state
请求它通过状态的会话
service endpoint that could be the local
可能是本地的服务端点
development case or pointing to a cloud
开发案例或指向云
1 then once you have the state service
1，然后一旦您有状态服务
session you say cloud map I'm sorry you
会议，你说云图，对不起你
say session get map the architecture of
说会话获取地图的架构
this to do is application uses a single
这是应用程序使用单个
data structure a single cloud map called
数据结构称为单个云图
two do's and and we store all of the two
两个做，我们存储所有两个
duties where the keys are
关键所在的职责
uu IDs and the values are the JSON data
uu ID和值是JSON数据
structures that have properties for user
具有用户属性的结构
text and completed or not very simple
文字和完成或不是很简单
three element data structure in the Java
Java中的三元素数据结构
case it's very similar you have a
情况非常相似，你有一个
session with a factory method called
使用称为工厂方法的会话
create that takes the URL of the state
创建带有状态URL的创建
service and then you say again get
服务，然后您再说一次
mapped passing to dues and this Java
映射传递给会费和此Java
example here we are going to be saving
这里的例子，我们将要保存
this user filter because most of the
此用户过滤器，因为大多数
queries that we're dealing with and
我们正在处理的查询和
filter out the user I mentioned that
过滤掉我提到的用户
each entry has a user property in it and
每个条目中都有一个用户属性，并且
in the map we're storing entries from
在地图中，我们存储来自
all of the different users of the
所有的不同用户
service so we only want to deal with the
服务，所以我们只想处理
two dues that are relevant to the
与
currently logged in user so that's why
当前登录的用户，这就是为什么
this user filter is employed here and
在这里使用该用户过滤器，并且
finally let's look at the go one the go
终于让我们看一看
one we have a new cloud map builder
我们有一个新的云地图生成器
passing the host and port and also the
通过主机和端口，以及
name and then we have access to this
名称，然后我们可以访问它
cloud map and you can see that it's go
云图，你可以看到它去了
of course because we have the multiple
当然，因为我们有多重
error response and we're using a builder
错误响应，我们正在使用一个生成器
pattern here maybe now let's look into
模式，也许现在让我们来看看
using the cloud map client this is the
使用云地图客户端，这是
most important
最重要的
the Code walkthrough here and it
代码演练在这里和它
provides Java eight map like user
提供像用户一样的Java八图
experience with server-side code
具有服务器端代码的经验
execution filtering querying aggregation
执行过滤查询聚合
and event streaming and will encounter
和事件流，将遇到
all of these aspects as we go through
我们经历的所有这些方面
the code let's go to the go one first
代码让我们先去吧
we'll show the simple pudding and
我们将展示简单的布丁和
removing what alright so we've got our
删除好吧，所以我们有了
cloud map and we're simply putting it so
云图，我们只是这样说
very simple there for delete
删除很简单
we've got cloud map remove and we also
我们已经删除了云图，我们还
have a remove all this is how the
有一个删除所有这是如何
implementation of clear completed is
执行清除完成是
done in the go
在旅途中完成
so if we say DC it's delete completed
因此，如果我们说DC，则删除已完成
and now that's what that is that will
现在就是那样
invoke this remove all so it's passing
调用此删除全部，以便通过
this filter and here the filter is
这个过滤器，这里的过滤器是
saying I would like you to remove the
说我希望您删除
entries where the completed property is
完整属性所在的条目
true now let's look at the querying and
现在，让我们来看一下查询和
aggregation here that appears on the
此处出现的汇总
list client our list method rather so
列出客户我们的列表方法
we're saying here's a filter again just
我们是说这又是一个过滤器
for give me the users give me the two
给我，用户给我两个
dues from the current user then we have
来自当前用户的会费
if the flag is active we're gonna add
如果该标志处于活动状态，我们将添加
equal is completed as false and if the
等于完成为假，如果
flag is negative we're going to say
标志是负的，我们要说
equals completed is true and we're
等于完成是真的，我们
enumerated the entry set so that's to do
枚举条目集，以便执行此操作
list we're passing this to do list which
列出我们正在传递的清单
is a reference to a go native map which
是对本地地图的引用
gets populated with the values that
填充了以下值
match the query let's take a look at the
匹配查询让我们看一下
JavaScript side to do API to j/s in the
JavaScript方面在j / s中做API
first one I want to show is not get
我想展示的第一个没有得到
listing all the to dues for the user so
列出用户的所有会费
here we're saying to dues which is the
在这里，我们要说的是
cloud map we got from server Jas we're
我们从服务器Jas获得的云图
passing saying values run over the user
传递说值贯穿用户
he equal to the current user and the
他等于当前用户，并且
JavaScript client uses JavaScript
JavaScript客户端使用JavaScript
promises so it happens everything that
保证一切都会发生
happens asynchronously I mean which
异步发生是指
means you can pass this then which you
意味着你可以通过这个然后你
pass a function reference and here once
通过功能参考，这里一次
we get the values back we're simply
我们获得了价值，我们只是
sending them down to the react client I
将它们发送给我的反应客户
mean let's look at let's see and they're
意思是让我们看看让我们看看
a little more interesting one would be
一个更有趣的是
updating the to-do text here we go so
在这里更新待办事项文本
here we're calling the invoke method on
这里我们在调用调用方法
the map this is server-side processing
地图这是服务器端处理
so we're passing passing the UUID and
所以我们通过了UUID和
then here we're passing the event
那么我们在这里通过了活动
processor the processor is invoked and
处理器，处理器被调用，
this gives us the data local server-side
这为我们提供了数据本地服务器端
code execution so and then coherence is
代码执行，然后一致性是
a massively scalable multi node
大规模可扩展的多节点
architecture and your data is going to
架构，您的数据将
be replicated and as much as needs to be
被复制并尽可能多地被复制
in it takes advantage of the maximum
在它利用最大
network topology to give maximum
网络拓扑以提供最大的
resilience so if you have a very widely
弹性，如果您拥有广泛的
distributed network it will spread
它将传播的分布式网络
things out to reduce the chances of the
减少事情发生的机会
data being lost of course it won't be
数据丢失当然不会
lost in any case but reduce the chances
无论如何都输了，但减少了机会
of recovering and make it faster to come
恢复并使其更快地康复
back when it does come back anyhow we're
当它回来时，无论如何我们回来了
passing the entry processor and it will
通过入口处理器，它将
be executed on the node that has the
在具有以下条件的节点上执行
actual data so none of the other
实际数据，所以没有其他
partitions will need to be locked and
分区将需要锁定，
and we're saying update the text so it's
我们说的是更新文本，因此
an entry processor that just does
一个入口处理器
updating of a property and of course the
更新财产，当然
promise happens they're returned to the
承诺发生，他们回到了
404 the completion flag I mentioned this
404我提到了完成标志
earlier with the event the custom event
较早的事件，自定义事件
processor so here's where we're calling
处理器，这就是我们要调用的位置
toggle completed so that just calls that
切换完成，因此只需调用
Java code
Java代码
child show again real here or quick
儿童再次显示真实或快速
toggling the value of the completed
切换完成的价值
property okay let's take a look at the
属性好吧，让我们来看看
remove all here we're passing again with
删除所有我们再次通过的内容
two filters equal user and equal
两个过滤器等于用户和等于
completed is true let's take a look at
完成是真的，让我们来看看
the Java side to do is client Java
Java方面要做的是客户端Java
mmm-hmm
嗯嗯
so that we already saw how to create the
这样我们已经了解了如何创建
map let's just take a look at adding and
地图，让我们看一下添加和
removing very simple call them output
删除非常简单的调用它们的输出
clad might remove thought might remove
穿着可能会删除思想可能会删除
also you can see it's very similar the
你也可以看到它非常相似
filtering and querying right there so
在那里进行过滤和查询
here we're saying cloud map give me the
这里我们说的是云图给我
values that match the filter stream turn
与过滤器流匹配的值
on the streaming the Java eights
在Java 8的流式传输上
streaming and passing this map generate
流式传输并传递此地图生成
to do which generates this to do very
做这产生非常做
simple and here is the reducer so the
简单，这里是减速器，所以
Java eight map API is an implementation
Java 8 Map API是一个实现
of the MapReduce paradigm and so here's
的MapReduce范式，所以这是
the map and here's the reduce let's go
地图，这是reduce让我们开始吧
back to JavaScript and take a look at
回到JavaScript，看看
the events and this is how the clients
事件，这就是客户的方式
are able to become aware of what happens
能够意识到发生了什么
on the other side in the node
在节点的另一侧
application that's using server-sent
使用服务器发送的应用程序
events so the react application will
事件，因此react应用程序将
make a rest call for this thing which
休息一下这个东西
will return text event stream and then
将返回文本事件流，然后
we're filtering on the current user so
我们正在过滤当前用户，因此
give me the events for the user and
给我事件的用户和
we're sending her at we're installing
我们在安装时派她去
several different listeners for insert
几种不同的插入侦听器
update and delete so in each case we're
更新和删除，因此在每种情况下
simply sending an SSE down to the client
只需将SSE发送给客户端
and if we look at the client code
如果我们看客户端代码
components app is you can see here we're
组件应用程序，您可以在这里看到我们
creating the event source and that makes
创建事件源，这使得
the rest call gets back to the event
其余的电话回到事件
source and we're
来源，我们
the different event listeners that
不同的事件监听器
interact with our to do domain
与我们的待办事项互动
application looks good how the events
应用程序看起来不错，事件如何
work and go did you use go okay here we
工作去你用了吗
are passing an event subscriber to do
正在通过事件订阅者来做
entry event subscriber this is a struct
进入事件订阅者，这是一个结构
that uses this client subscription
使用此客户端订阅
that's the data type that comes from the
这是来自
go client and it has a few methods you
去客户端，它有一些方法，你
need to implement on subscribe on
需要在订阅上实施
complete on-air and on next and here in
完成直播以及接下来和此处的
the next case if it's one or two that
下一种情况，如果是一两个
means updating either the one is
意味着更新一个是
inserting two is updating we get a new
插入两个正在更新，我们得到一个新
of to do entry and we either update it
要做输入，我们要么更新它
or just you know deal with it okay is
或者只是你知道处理好吗
that paradigm for dealing with maps so
这种处理地图的范式
should be familiar to go programmers
去程序员应该很熟悉
mm-hmm and let's see how we hook that up
mm-hmm，让我们看看如何将其连接起来
here so to do entry event subscriber
在这里这样做进入事件订阅者
right there similar to what we saw on
就在那里，就像我们看到的一样
the other clients cloud map events
其他客户端云地图事件
filter equals on user and then subscribe
过滤器等于用户，然后订阅
passing our the address of the
通过我们的地址
subscriber that we've just created here
我们刚刚在此处创建的订阅者
alright
好的
so we can see that uh cloud map is
这样我们可以看到呃云图是
distributed map with a lot more goodies
具有更多优点的分布式地图
on top of it we have this distributed
最重要的是，我们已经分发了
persistence from coherence shared
一致性带来的持久性
storage is not required and need its
不需要存储，需要存储
discourage it also supports snapshots
不鼓励它也支持快照
and archiving of the distributed state
和归档分布式状态
so you can see lots of different
这样您可以看到很多不同的地方
topologies are possible here and we have
拓扑在这里是可能的，我们有
at Oracle here a whole new platform that
在Oracle，这里有一个全新的平台
we're building we brought you with the
我们正在建立，我们为您带来了
community Java EE and now the community
Java EE和现在的社区
is taking it over and we have seen
正在接管，我们已经看到
things changing a bit and micro services
事情改变了一点，微服务
and serverless and clout and we feel
和无服务器和影响力，我们感到
that a new approach is needed for these
这些需要一种新的方法
kind of applications so we have a micro
一种应用程序，所以我们有一个微型
services project that's going to be
服务项目将是
coming out and we also a job one we
出来，我们也是一份工作
announce the FN serverless project and
宣布FN无服务器项目并
tying these together is the state
把这些绑在一起是国家
project the state service that I'm
投影我所处的国家服务
talking to you about here today so
今天在这里和你聊天
without the state service you know you
没有国家服务，你就知道你
could bring your own thing you can use
可以带上自己可以使用的东西
some other kinds of things Redis or what
Redis或其他一些东西
have you but those are not as good
有你但是那些不那么好
tightly integrated to provide an overall
紧密集成以提供整体
value experience with the other two
珍惜其他两个经验
things and also in addition we're better
事情，此外我们更好
performance than any of those
性能比任何一个
off-the-shelf ones - we have a demo
现成的-我们有一个演示
based on the FN project and this is the
基于FN项目，这是
vista license plate demo it is a micro
Vista的车牌演示它是一个微
services based thing but it's actually
基于服务的东西，但实际上
even more micro than that it's function
甚至比它的功能还微
based function as a service so you could
基于功能的服务，因此您可以
think of micro services I'm sorry you
想起微服务，对不起你
could think of functions as like the
可以认为功能就像
tiniest possible micro service it's a
最小的微服务，这是一个
single method invocation they are
它们是单方法调用
intended to be spun up and turned down
打算旋转并拒绝
for each request now you might observe
对于每个请求，您现在都可以观察到
how do you deal with Java in that case
在这种情况下，您如何处理Java
well you can mark your Java based
好吧，您可以标记基于Java
function as a service function as a hot
充当服务充当热点
function
功能
and this will enable the JVM to stay hot
这将使JVM保持高温
for a specified time period we the
在指定的时间段内，
default is two minutes so if you get no
默认是两分钟，所以如果没有
requests in more than two minutes the
超过两分钟的请求
JVM will spin down but in production
JVM将会降级，但正在生产中
you're expecting to get more you know
您期望获得更多了解
than that so furthermore billing wise
除此之外，更明智的计费方式
we're not going to be charging for the
我们不会为
spin-up and spin-down time of the VM
VM的加速时间和加速时间
because we know that Java is being
因为我们知道Java正在
interpreted and being subject to
解释并受制于
strategies like just in time and ahead
像时间和未来一样的策略
of time compilation and all of the
时间编译和所有
hotspot type optimizations there we know
我们知道热点类型优化
that the VM gets better over time so
随着时间的流逝，VM变得越来越好
we're taking that into account let's
我们考虑到这一点，让我们
talk about the domain so this license
谈论域名，所以这个许可证
plate demo what it does is get some
平板演示它的功能是得到一些
license plates and tweet the map right
车牌并在地图上发布鸣叫权
you can imagine a alert service where
您可以想象一个警报服务
you want to monitor license plate
您要监控车牌
activities so we have a number of
活动，所以我们有很多
different functions that are here one of
这里的不同功能之一
the two of them are written in Ruby
他们两个是用Ruby编写的
four of them are written in Java maybe
其中四个是用Java编写的
one of them is written and go and
其中之一被写走
another one is written in Python what
另一个是用Python写的
happens is the scraper service queries
发生的是刮板服务查询
Flickr to get license plate images that
Flickr获取车牌图像
contain license plates then we call the
包含车牌，那么我们称
ALPR
阿尔普
automatic license plate recognition
自动车牌识别
software as a separate function there
软件作为单独的功能存在
which will do OCR on the license plate
这将在车牌上进行OCR
and also give me the coordinates of
还给我坐标
where the license plate is in the image
车牌在图像中的位置
we have a detect diplucate service that
我们有一个检测二元服务，
will prevent us from taking action on
会阻止我们采取行动
plates we've already seen then we have a
我们已经看过的盘子，然后我们有一个
draw service which uses image magic to
使用图像魔术来进行绘图的服务
draw that box based on the coordinates
根据坐标画那个盒子
that were from the detects function and
来自检测功能和
then we have an alert service which will
然后我们有一个警报服务
send it out over Twitter we also have
通过Twitter发送出去，我们也有
these ones on the bottom
这些在底部
progress alert manager and publish which
进度警报管理器并发布
sort of coordinate the UI for this thing
协调此事物的用户界面
and also the progress bar and the alert
还有进度条和警报
manager for sort of providing state for
经理提供某种状态
how the admin will deal with the tweets
管理员如何处理推文
as they come through these services here
当他们通过这些服务来到这里
the ones that I mentioned were written
我提到的是写的
in Java are talking to the state service
Java中的人正在与状态服务对话
directly and we could take a look at how
直接，我们可以看看如何
this runs so let me show you what this
运行，所以让我告诉你这是什么
looks like in practice
在实践中看起来像
okay here is the Vista state service
好的，这是Vista状态服务
demo so we're going to reload this page
演示，所以我们将重新加载此页面
and click go and we're going to send
然后点击开始，我们将要发送
some data through the system so this
通过系统的一些数据，所以这
will be querying Flickr and kicking off
将查询Flickr并开始
the whole run of functions and indeed we
整个功能，实际上我们
now see some functions coming through
现在看到一些功能通过
the system the first function to be
系统的第一个功能是
invoked is the detect plates function
调用检测板功能
and the next one will be the draw
下一个是抽奖
function and while that's running
功能，而正在运行
ultimately our goal is to get to the
最终，我们的目标是达到
alert Java function and we can see but
提醒Java函数，我们可以看到，但是
we don't have any tweets sent out just
我们没有发出任何推文
yet on this run but we have been running
尚未运行，但我们一直在运行
this demo for a while you can also see
这个演示一段时间，您还可以看到
here the progress of the functions
这里的功能进度
flowing through the system here you can
流过系统，您可以
see how many milliseconds it took for
看看花了多少毫秒
each of the different phases and we have
每个不同的阶段，我们都有
a tag map here that will include the
此处的标记图将包括
license plate data the you know the
你知道的车牌数据
state for which the license plate
车牌所针对的州
belongs getting our C and some drawers
属于我们的C和一些抽屉
come along
一起来
and we should eventually get next to the
我们最终应该靠近
clerk potentially if we notice here we
如果我们在这里注意到，我们可能会有店员
have 27 plate matches by state so far so
到目前为止，各州有27盘比赛
we should expect this number to increase
我们应该期望这个数字会增加
as more plates are detected and flow
随着更多板块的检测和流动
through the system and while that's
通过系统，而那是
running let's take a look at the Java
运行让我们看一下Java
code for the alert service alert job so
警报服务警报作业的代码，因此
this is an example of a Java based
这是一个基于Java的示例
function and the function is a service
功能和功能是服务
platform it's just a simple Java class
平台，它只是一个简单的Java类
and it has a handle request method which
它有一个句柄请求方法
is the one that's invoked by the
是由调用的
function service and when this method is
功能服务以及何时使用此方法
invoked we get the JSON and we pull out
调用后，我们获取JSON，然后退出
the alert cloud map and we do a number
警报云图，我们做了一些
of manipulations on it there you saw
你在那里看到的操纵
that one it went up from 27 to 28 so the
它从27上升到28
state service is interacted with in this
状态服务与此交互
application by virtue of this number of
凭借此数量的申请
properties but the state filter here you
属性，但状态过滤器在这里
can put in a regular expression that
可以放一个正则表达式
will only tweak through things that
只会调整那些
match a certain state for example and
匹配某个状态，例如
you can also have another service that
您还可以享受另一项服务
will filter out duplicates if you don't
如果不这样做，将过滤出重复项
want to see those okay now we went up to
想看看现在还可以吗
29 so if we go back to the graph we
29所以如果我们回到图表
should expect to see some alerts on
应该期望看到一些警报
there there's the two and we should also
有两个，我们也应该
reload the Twitter and we should expect
重新加载Twitter，我们应该期待
to see some tweets in there there are
看那里的一些推文
okay 35 seconds ago and 53 seconds ago
好的35秒前和53秒前
and another pattern that I wanted to
还有我想要的另一种模式
show which was similar to the to-do demo
显示与待办演示类似
that I did is how you get the cloud map
我所做的就是你如何获得云图
so you have state service endpoint which
所以你有状态服务端点
again is a remote in this case it's
在这种情况下再次是一个遥控器
remote running in the cloud and we're
远程运行在云中，我们
saying endpoint session create endpoint
说端点会话创建端点
of and then we have a number of
的，然后我们有一些
different maps the simple to do app had
简单的应用程序所拥有的不同地图
just one this one has quite a few and
这个只有一个
the one I want to focus on next is this
接下来我要重点介绍的是
request progress map this is how the
请求进度图，这是如何
progress bar is drawn and how this table
进度条以及此表的绘制方式
is populated with data here so we have
在这里填充了数据，所以我们有
two services the alert Java interacts
警报Java交互的两种服务
with this by putting some data in it
通过将一些数据放入其中
updating the progress so it's calling
更新进度，因此它正在调用
the invoke method which sends this
发送此的invoke方法
function over to the server to run so
运行到服务器上运行
let's look at what that looks like
让我们看一下看起来像什么
update progress this is a cloud function
更新进度，这是一个云功能
that we're serializing and setting so
我们正在序列化和设置
this code runs on the server side and
此代码在服务器端运行，
again if we wanted to deal with code
再次，如果我们想处理代码
deployment that was outside of just this
超出此范围的部署
lambda you can interact with maven
您可以与Maven互动的Lambda
artifacts that you've previously
您之前拥有的工件
deployed to the cloud service and the
部署到云服务和
other service I wanted to show is the
我想展示的其他服务是
progress update service this one also
进度更新服务这也
interacts with the cloud map request
与云地图请求进行交互
progress cloud map it also has an update
进度云图也有更新
progress method which is kind of similar
类似的进度方法
in fact it could be shared between the
实际上，它可以在
two different services but we haven't
两种不同的服务，但我们还没有
done that yet okay and you've got three
做到了，还好，你有三个
more tweets let's just reload
更多推文让我们重新加载
Twitter is being a little slow too okay
Twitter有点慢也可以
actually they didn't give us anymore yet
其实他们还没有给我们
so well that's enough it gets the point
很好就足够了
across to summarize the serverless state
总结一下无服务器状态
service is infinitely scalable it's
服务是无限可扩展的
resilient continuously available it has
有弹性，持续可用
that map based continuously ubiquitous
该地图基于无处不在
he understood burning model data local
他了解本地刻录模型数据
processing and pay-as-you-go so
处理并按需付款
hopefully it's coming to a cloud near
希望它临近云
you
您